## IAN JAMES, II

Nashville, TN 37217

(678) 325-8697 | ianjames2@protonmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-james-ii-1aa8551a5/

https://github.com/IanJames2

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

As I separated from the military, I wanted to restart my career by doing something I would enjoy doing while being in a comfortable work environment. From a physical perspective, software development provides a comfortable work environment for me, nonetheless. Mentally, as a software developer I enjoy the challenge of achieving a task assigned to me to better my team and/or contribute to an end goal for a particular application. I understand that being a software developer requires years of experience to reach a senior level. I relish the fact that I have a long journey ahead of me. In retaliation to the knowledge that is required of me to create software, I have devised several multi-year plans that will add to my skills and expertise in the long run. What I have accomplished thus-far in training for software developer positions are mentioned in some form or fashion below.

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE**

## Coding Dojo | Burbank, California Software Developer Student Intern

December 2020 - April 2021

Learned the fundamentals necessary to build out CRUD functionality using Python, JavaScript, and Java. Topics Covered for each stack include:

Java: MVC Framework, ORM, SQL, JPQL, Test-Driven Development, Dependency Injection and Inversion of Control, CRUD Operations, Authentication/Login, Web Development Java

MERN: OOP in JS, Ajax Requests, MVC Framework, NoSQL DB Design, CRUD Operations

Python: OOP in Python, SQL Queries and ERD Diagrams, Web Security Basics, CRUD Operations, MVC Framework and Design Patterns, Test-Driven Application

## Nashville Software School | Nashville, Tennessee Full Stack Software Developer

May 2021 - November 2021

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp anchoring learning with both individual and team-based projects. Tech Stack: .Net / C#; React.js; JavaScript; HTML5; CSS3; SQL fundamentals.

- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub Projects & Issue Tracking
- Styled applications with CSS and Bootstrap
- JavaScript fundamentals including ES6 modules
- Database/API utilizing JSON, C#, SQL, promises, and axios calls
- Application design through wireframes, and building ERD's to create Front End and Back End Website Functionality

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

• JSP	• Tomcat	• JPA
• APIs	• AJAX	• NPM
• MVC	• React	• Express
• HTML	• Python	<ul> <li>MySQL</li> </ul>
• CSS	<ul> <li>Django</li> </ul>	• DB Browser / SQLite
• Node.js	• Flask	• OOP
• Java	<ul> <li>Spring</li> </ul>	API Design / Postman

## IAN JAMES, II

Nashville, TN 37217

(678) 325-8697 | ianiames2@protonmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-james-ii-1aa8551a5/

https://github.com/IanJames2

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Coding Dojo | Burbank, California

December 2020 - April 2021

Java: By adding a middle table for the user, and the user's occupation, I compiled a backend database using Spring Tool Suite and MySQL. This backend application will allow a user to store permanent data related to a job, with a job rating.

MERN: Created a full stack application that adds an apartment to a Mongo dB database with the option of updating or deleting the apartment information.

Python: Created a full stack application that adds a book with an author, publisher, and date written with the option of deletion or updating the book information using Django with Flask.

## Nashville Software School | Nashville, Tennessee

May 2021 - November 2021

React JS Front-end Capstone: Created a front-end application that condenses educational research related to personal endeavors for prospective degree seeking students who want to continue furthering their education while working full-time.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# United States Navy Selective Reserves | Nashville, Tennessee

January 2021 - Present

Aircraft Mechanic

Perform sequential reserve duty physical health screenings and off-duty naval occupational training to maintain a deployable status for critical warfare obligations and servitude.

- Received physical drilling mandates on a monthly and/or bi-monthly basis to ensure compliance of United States Naval Reservist drilling requirements.
  - Committed to off-duty in-rate training and volunteer operations in correspondence to assist the United States Navy as they support and defend the U.S. constitution, as well as American democracy.

## United States Navy | Norfolk, Virginia

December 2016 - December 2020

## Aircraft Mechanic

Conducted preflight and periodic inspections of multiple airframes ensuring the safety of flight crew personnel by identifying any malfunctions or discrepancies in mechanical and electrical systems.

- Stored, transported, and distributed jet fuel to multiple aircraft to ensure they received the appropriate amounts of fuel according to their flight plans ensuring all flight teams were mission capable.
- Conducted regular maintenance for landing gear systems, flight components, and the outer surface of aircraft.

## **EDUCATION | CERTIFICATIONS**

Associate of Applied Science, Air Traffic Control | Middle Georgia State University (June 2015)

Control Tower Operator Certificate | Valdosta Regional Airport (June 2013)

Limited Aviation Weather Reporting Station Certificate | Advanced Air Traffic Control Training Program (June 2013)

**TWIC** | Transportation Worker Identification Credential (May 2020)

Certification of Completion | Coding Dojo (April 2021)

Training with Completion of Capstone Project in C# (In Progress) | Nashville Software School (Expected: November 2021)